Guide to the Lyman Whiting Papers, 1713-1955
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lyman Whiting papers 1713-1955
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Whiting, Lyman, 1817-1906.
1.5 linear feet Extent: 310 Items
Whiting was a Massachusetts clergyman. The collection consists of materials documenting Whiting's professional life as a Congregational minister.
whitinglyman
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Lyman Whiting Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1973.
Biographical Note
Lyman Whiting was a Massachusetts clergyman and political nominee. He attended the Theological Institute at East Windson Hill and Andover Theological Seminary, 1840-1842.
Collection Overview
Collection consists of materials documenting his professional life as a Congregational minister. Records in the collection outline his career, name apointments, offices held, publications, and nominations received. There is also personal correspondence, a 1713 will, a letter from B.B. Edwards, some genealogical information, and a narrative that appears to be his description of his sensations shortly before his death.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Clergy -- Massachusetts; Edwards, B. B.
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Correspondence, 1788-1861 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1862-1955 (Box 2)
  - Legal Papers, 1713-1848
  - Financial Papers, 1850-1863
  - Addresses and Writings, 1830-1837
  - Genealogy
  - Clippings
  - Printed Material
  - Photographs